How do brands fund growth? You're doing
5 million a year, you're doing 10
million a year. How are you actually
buying inventory? How are you paying
yourself? How are you paying your team?
How do you make it so you can go from 5
or 10 to 50 million without taking
investment?
>> And we were promised. We had four vice
presidents of Wells Fargo in my office
saying, "You are getting this. We love
your company. When you get to 500
million, we're still going to be funding
you." Not only are we canceling the 20
to 25 million, we're not going to give
you that. We want the $2 million back
now.
>> We started having money going in our
Shopify and they would take it out to
pay back the loan so we couldn't even
pay our people.
>> How long did it take you to recover?
Welcome to the Operators Podcast. My
name is Mike Beckham and we are proudly
brought to you by Fulfill, After Sell,
Rich Panel, North Beam, Saris Analytics,
and Post Script. Without further ado,
onto the pod.
>> [snorts]
>> Everywhere we turn right now, there is
some world-changing AI announcement. And
I think the trick for us operators is
figuring out what's actually going to
help our business. Is this stuff saving
us money? Is it helping us grow revenue?
Is it helping us grow profit? Like,
where is the freaking ROI? Jason, for
Hexclad, tell everybody what is actually
working for you guys. Yeah, look, I'm
laser-like focused on implementing AI
wherever we can to just make us more
efficient. Fulfill has been huge for us.
Like, my team is constantly using
Fulfill's new CLI tool and MCP features
with Claude. They're now able to query
Fulfill data. They They can write code
up dashboards.
Um I mean, we get these awesome
dashboards on operations and and Fulfill
continues to build things that are
actually
useful for brands. It's hard to see what
kind of AI work is valuable and what
isn't. Sure, like, there's so much out
there, so much coming at us, but Fulfill
seems to be giving us things we can
really use
to get more efficient.
What's up, everybody? Welcome to the
Operators Podcast. We have one of the
best guests we've ever had coming back
for a second appearance. Curtis, he's a
big ball of energy. He's somehow younger
than me. He's in great shape. He's doing
jump rope every single day. Curtis, how
are you, man? The world treats me well
as we talked about.
Dude, uh [snorts] it's always so
pleasure It's always a pleasure to have
you on here. Matt, how are you doing,
brother? I'm doing great, man. Like,
life is life is really kind to me, too.
I'm with Curtis.
It's a topic that we've talked about,
but we've been asked to talk about it
more. It is how do brands fund growth?
So,
you know, you're doing 5 million a year,
you're doing 10 million a year. How are
you actually buying inventory? How are
you paying yourself? How are you paying
your team? How do you make it so you can
go from 5 or 10 to 50 million without
taking investment? Maybe taking
investment is part of that. We're going
to talk about three different stories
today. Curtis, we're going to open with
you. I think you have one of the most
compelling punch-in-your-face stories
you've ever heard. So, so set the stage.
Where was Portland Leather Goods when
when this story took place? Okay, I got
to jump a little bit before this and
lead in, okay? Cuz I started this thing
in a garage.
And so, there was no capital. Like,
there was just like There was one time I
went to do an art festival with our
stuff and I had to like no gas, so I had
to like basically cruise in with no gas,
make enough cash that day to get a hotel
and to do it. So, we started with
nothing, okay?
But even as we said, "Let's go from art
festivals to Etsy and Etsy to Shopify."
I would go do art festivals to make
enough cash to make payroll the next
week.
So, I was always doing this type of a
thing. So,
we started getting bigger and bigger and
we moved to Shopify and we're getting in
the tens of millions and I started my
company with Wells Fargo because a block
away from where I started in the garage,
there's a Wells Fargo. So, what do you
do? You go to a bank. And I walked in, I
started a business account. And when we
needed a little bit of money, they kept
looking back three years
and saying, "Hey, we can give you a
little bit." So, they ended up giving us
like 1.5 to 2 million dollars.
But somebody in Wells Fargo believed in
us and he kept coming over and seeing
our growth. So, they moved us to this
new level and they're like, "We want to
give you 20 million dollars to grow your
company."
And Curtis, this is a This is a
revolver, right? So, so uh
it's a it's a line of credit you can
access at any point. And and what were
the terms of the revolver? So, it's it's
going from 1.5 to 20 million. Can you
use it for anything you want? Are there
covenants attached to it?
Um there's always covenants and you
don't know what those covenants are
uh other than yeah, we could use it for
inventory. We could use it for anything.
Now, the problem was they needed audits,
so we did an audit. They needed this, we
needed that. So, we spent a year getting
everything in line to get this and we
were promised. We had four vice
presidents of Wells Fargo in my office
saying,
"You are getting this. It is done. Oh my
We love your company. When you get to
500 million, we're still going to be
funding you, right?" I'm like, "Thank
you. They believe in me."
Well, we were building a shoe company at
the same time where I was 12, 14 million
into down payments, leather, molds,
shoes already arriving with this new
brand.
And what happened is the Silicon Valley
Bank had their problem and they became
insolvent
right at the exact same time.
So, we said, "Hey, we want to sign the
paper on that 20, 25 million dollar line
of credit, but not just the 2 million we
have now." And they're like, "Oh yeah,
that'll be next week. That'll be next
week. That'll be next week." And all of
a sudden, the guy we knew called me up
and he said, "We have to have a meeting
tomorrow. I am so sorry." And the guy
had tears in his eyes.
And I'm like, "What is wrong?" We met
again and they're like, "No, you broke a
covenant
by this because your margins, because
you have this inventory, because you
trusted us, you bought inventory ahead
of time
because we promised the money and
because we delayed in giving you the
money, now your books look out of
whack."
And so, happens that the day before the
CEO of Wells Fargo came out and said
they were going to be more cautious and
start bringing money back in, not giving
it out. They said, "Not only are we
canceling the 20 to 25 million, we're
not going to give you that. We want the
$2 million back now."
And we started having money going in our
Shopify and it would go into our Wells
Fargo and they would take it out to pay
back the loan so we couldn't even pay
our people.
And then they said, "Oh, that building
you bought, that was a Wells Fargo loan
and that was based on your company doing
well and now that we took your company
over, we want you to go from that 3% you
had on your building to a new 8% loan to
refinance your building."
And we have suppliers all over the world
that we can't pay.
Like, we're just stuck. I was in New
York I when I the day I heard, I flew
back. We had a meeting room and I said,
"We are doing this." Boom, boom. We just
figured it out. We made cuts. We
overcame it. And we came out stronger
and I told everybody that day. I said,
"This is the type that you look back on
in a couple years and say, 'We would
have screwed up if we got the 25
million. Let's be better. What are we
going to learn from this?'" And we got
more profitable, more lean, and now
we've grown and our profitability and
our growth rate is staggering now. We
would not have had that profit. I would
have been too loose with that 25
million. The fact that we never used it
and never needed it, I think it made us
stronger.
Sean here to tell you about Saris
Analytics and Saris Pulse. Ridge is
profitable every single day and we've
taken that super seriously since we
built this business. We track
contribution margin by day. We look at
the SKUs we sell every single day. And
we have to do this manually up until
Saris Analytics came out. We take all of
our SKU-level data. We build it into the
data warehouse. Everything that goes
into making a true P&L, I get on a
day-to-day basis. Saris Pulse gives you
clarity so your CLO and your CFO and
your CMO start speaking the same
language. Contribution margin shifts
teams away from hoping profits survive
the season to managing them in real
time. Book a walkthrough with the Saris
Pulse team today. Click the link in the
description and thank you, Saris, for
bringing you this show.
How long did it take you to
uh recover?
It was a year of hell.
It was a year of hell. It's you know,
our people here in Mexico as I'm in
Mexico and our CFO in Portland,
like, they just had to tell 10, 15
people a week, "We can't pay you.
We can't pay you." Yeah, could you
please still deliver the leather or this
product or the boxes or the packaging or
can we pay you next month? Can you do
that? Like, that was just It's constant
for a year of juggling those finances.
And it's one of those things that
entrepreneurs never see.
They'll hear the story of you staying up
late at night and you can't sleep
because of this,
but they don't know that it's a year
long of just having conversation day
after day. It's like, I'm sure if broke
people who get debt collectors calling
them every day and they're like, "Dude,
I don't got a job. I can't give you any
money." That's what it's like, but we
were optimistic at the same time. And
why were we optimistic? Because I'm
optimistic. I knew we would overcome it.
Like, I just don't let doubt enter my
mind. I let problems come in, but we
were able to solve it just out of sheer
stubbornness.
Did
did that sour you on debt completely?
Because, you know, in that year, I'm
sure another bank or another lender
would have came and given you money. But
by that point, were you just so burnt
out you're like, "I'm just going to I'm
going to do the hard thing. I'm going to
make this company lean." Or what was the
thought process? It didn't It did not
sour me on debt. It soured me on dealing
with organizations where the person in
the room that you're talking to isn't
the power person, right? We had all of
these people saying, "It's good. It's
good. Just do these things." And then
someone else up the chain said, "I can
read these numbers a different way and
it can come out poorly."
I mean, that sucks.
Yeah. Also, just like, you know, even
the fact that there's four vice
presidents, you just described with
dealing with the financial system. It's
like I'm like, "Guys, just you guys are
worth $200 billion. Just give me the
loan. I'm good for it." And there's 9
billion people you got to talk to. Um
Matt
I was going to say, Curtis, did you
Were there a lot of personal guarantees
with this stuff?
Everything's me. Everything's me. So,
uh
Yeah, you know, when the when If the
company goes bust, I go bust. Like
beyond that, they'll come after you.
Now, we've got really good trust
attorneys and all of those folks now.
Since that's happened, I've hired the
people who set up everything in in a
more careful way and and and do all of
that. But I didn't know at the time.
Like we're too busy building. We're too
busy growing to worry about all of that
stuff. But you know
we brought those folks in to shield
ourselves in the future. But shield
yourself. If the company goes out of
business today
I got no money. Like it's all in the
company. Yeah, I think that part I think
it's just it's a call out, Curtis. Just
personal guarantees when you're early in
building a company, they're usually
required to get any kind of borrowing in
place. Uh
that's the lender's way of like having a
backstop.
The
I'm just I think like it's probably a
good idea that as you get your business
to a better place that you want to start
to try to rip those out of any debt that
you have. Oh, without a doubt. Yeah, go
ahead, Sean.
Uh I was going to say, you know, to to
frame the conversation. When you're
getting started, when when you were
selling on Etsy, right, or or the art
fairs, like
the way to fund your growth is by any
means necessary. This is when people are
using credit cards. This is when people
using savings or friends and family.
Like you're not going to be able to go
to a bank and get a loan when you don't
have a business. Like like Curtis, you
said this, the bank wanted the past 3
years financials. And the financial
system in America
a lot of really awesome positive things
about it. I think bankruptcy is like a
very uniquely American thing. But one of
the the the downsides is
it favors the established, right? Like
when you're getting started, the only
way to fund stuff is yourself.
And that's why I think, you know, drop
shipping was so popular is because you
can buy just ads and someone else
completes all the inventory purchases. I
feel that era is behind us. I don't
think you can really drop ship and
become a millionaire. So, to build a
business like Portland Leather Goods or
Pela or or Ridge, you know
all the funding has to come from
somewhere. And when when we got started,
the funding came out of our pocket, too.
Um Now, Curtis, how far were you able to
take that $2 million
line of credit? We were already doing
well, you know, because we had had years
of just growth of cash flow doing cash
flow cash doing cash flow. And at the
time we were doubling every year.
And when people today, when I talk to
small businesses, 1 to 5, 10, 20 million
I say, "We doubled." And they said, "How
do you do that with cash flow?" And I
said, "It's not possible to do it on
your own, but you still have to figure
out a way to do it anyhow, right?" Like
it just doesn't seem like it works from
buying inventory, putting down deposits.
By the time you get paid, paying
everybody else off, it doesn't seem
possible. But being in that scrappy
sense I remember one time we're in our
building and I knocked down a wall
because I didn't want to pay somebody
5,000 to knock it. So, I always was the
one like everyone would go home and I
would just like just take things and
knock down a wall. And there's this huge
electrical thing with all these wires
coming out of it. So, we called
Somebody's like, "That's dangerous.
Let's call an electrician." And I said,
"Yeah, yeah, whatever." And the
electrician came over and he's like
eyeballing and he said, "Yeah, it'd be
about 20,000 for you to get rid of
that." And I said, "Thank you." And he
left. And I said, "Turn off the power."
And I just like went cut every damn
wire. The whole thing fell down, wrapped
them up, and I said, "Now, let's call
somebody and say, 'Hey, finish off these
wires, not cut the thing off.'" And I'm
like, "Hey, there's $20,000 that I
needed that I did. There's pictures of
me standing on 40-ft ladders on the very
top reaching to paint a corner. Well,
you do the things you have to do. That's
what being an entrepreneur is. Like,
'Oh, I could pay somebody 2,000 or I
could spend a couple hours doing it or a
weekend.'" I did that at the beginning
with our building. Everyone would leave
on Friday I would start doing
construction, work all day Saturday,
Sunday, come in early Monday morning and
clean everything up for the gains we
did. And then people would come in and
say
"Is it a little dusty? Do you Do you see
some dust?" And I'm like, "I just spent
24 hours this weekend doing this big
project and you come in and you're like,
'There's dust on my computer.'"
But you do it because I don't want to
give that money away cuz I need that
money for growth. So, when you're small,
you do that. When you get medium, you
start understanding why someone who's
going to give you 5 and 10 million is
better.
But you have to watch who these people
are.
The bigger these companies, the more
that they say, "This is how it's done."
the more I say, "This dude doesn't have
a clue of how it's done." He studied
finance. He went in. He's a lower middle
management of somebody making promises,
doesn't know what they're talking about.
I don't trust them.
I'm going to trust people that are
trustworthy. You know,
uh
Oh, I think one of the hardest lessons
I've had to learn cuz so
as I think you guys know this. Sean
definitely knows this. Like we have
investors.
So, we have like a cap table. We have
debt from
like well, we have
convertible debt, right? So, it's
supposed to convert into equity.
I can tell you like one of the hardest
lessons I've had to learn dealing with
outside equity investors and lenders is
that you're actually never really sure
what their internal incentives are at
any given moment in time.
So, you think like
I've always thought everybody just wants
to make money.
So, like the profit motive is the number
one thing. But that's actually not
always true at funds.
Right? Or inside of banks. Sometimes
there's political motives. Sometimes
it's self-preservation. Sometimes
they're raising a new fund
and they just need to look good to LPs
to raise the new fund.
So, there's a lot of things that
actually
What you're making me think of, Curtis,
is just this. Like there's a lot of
things that when you start to deal with
other people's money uh that you are not
privy to. You do not know what they're
contending with on a given day. Like the
average fund
whether you're getting debt or equity,
there's GPs and LPs. The GPs are who you
deal with. The LPs are who the GPs deal
with.
And
dude, the last 3 years, LPs have not
been great to their GPs.
Uh it's been hell in most funds.
And a lot of that winds up bleeding down
to the operators.
So, I'm with you, man. I think that like
you really If you're going to take
money, doesn't matter what kind of money
you're taking, you really need to know
the other like the people on the other
side of the table. Um
and just know that their incentives are
going to change over time.
Curtis, you said something that I think
is really impactful. It's impossible,
but you have to do it anyway.
Um That That is That is growth in the
early days, man. I always tell people I
always meet a young kid and he's like,
you know, trying to double his business
or triple his business in a year. And I
always tell him, "Why are you doing
that?" Like because because like the
math doesn't work. Like if you actually
run out the equation, yeah, you cannot
have enough money to double while also
satisfying inventory demands now and
everything else. Like there needs to be
some slack in the system. But like you
said, you found out a way to make it to
to to make it happen, right? It's either
you getting loans that aren't really
loans from your supplier, right? So, you
get terms in your inventory, right? Or
you found some way to pre-order
inventory. I think Hudson did that over
a comfort. He's like, "Okay, I'm going
to get my money before I buy the
inventory." There has to be some slack
in the system to actually double because
the raw equation by itself just doesn't
work, no matter how big you are. You
cannot buy the current inventory and
next year's inventory and double it,
right?
With with the same amount of cash.
If you're scaling an e-commerce brand
today, ads alone aren't enough.
AfterSell focuses on the one moment that
every brand already owns, after
checkout, and turns the post-purchase
moment into more profit. Monetize every
order with post-purchase offers and
thank you page experiences without
disrupting checkout or hurting
conversion. Enterprise-grade tech used
by Gap, Ticketmaster, and Target. Now
driving results for brands like True
Classic, Hexclad, Ridge, and Jones Road.
I would know. This is the reason I ended
up buying three pants from Hexclad
instead of two. AfterSell has already
generated over $1 billion in additional
revenue for e-commerce brands. Revenue
that doesn't require more traffic or
higher CAC. So, check out AfterSell and
tell them that the operators sent you.
Matt said that incredibly well. He said
really understanding what the other
people want is the key. Not what they
the company has said they really want.
Not what the salesman says, but really
talking to them saying, "The more I know
about what your model is, what you're
really looking for I can change what I'm
doing so we work well together." That's
the same thing with sourcing, right?
Everyone thinks, "I'm going to pound
them down. I'm going to negotiate them
down. I'm going to push that down."
We've had to do deals with people where
I had to convince them. I watched last
night uh a operator's podcast of the two
of you talking about how if you're
likable, you get farther in business.
And that is so true because everyone
thinks negotiation, I got to be a hard
ass and tell these suppliers they need
to take this deal. The real key is
sitting them down with the room and
saying, "Hey, I understand how your
business runs. What can I do
to get more product at the right thing?
Where's your crunch point? Where are you
in Well, we need this and this. If I did
it this way, would that work out?" Now
you can get better terms. You're the
buddy. You're not the person fighting
them. You're Curtis who's being nice to
them. And that gives you the power. I
used to go back every year to all of our
leather suppliers because right now in
my building, I have 2.8 million square
feet of leather, okay? So, I have 6 to 7
million square feet just in this
building. Not counting all the product
and all the stuff that's in ships on the
way, right?
And I would tell everybody, "Hey guys, I
got I'm a wonderful guy. I love you to
death. You're not getting paid from
October 15th until December 2nd. Until
the money is in my account from
Thanksgiving, Black Friday, that
weekend,
I'm building product to sell. I'm not
paying you anything." And you tell them
ahead of time and you joke around about
enough and you treat them well,
they'll say, "Okay, we trust you.
Well, you'll just pay us in a couple
months, right?" Sure.
That's just people dealing with people.
And all of that is needed. Every one of
those things that you can do, get a tool
at a better price, get someone to work
for less,
uh extend those terms a little bit more.
Everything you can do,
you need in order if you're going to
double cuz the math doesn't work. I'm
dealing with Matt, you had something say
there.
No, I'm just wondering at like at what
point did you develop this sort of uh
There's like I feel like it when you're
early
in the journey,
you're much more reactive
when it comes to like cash cycles,
working capital. Like you basically
it's impossible, but you do it anyway,
right? Then at some point you develop a
bit of like proactive, I'm I'm more
thoughtful, I'm thinking through things,
I'm like I understand the company's
working capital calculations. Like
Basically like how does all this connect
together?
I'm just wondering like when did you
develop that, Curtis? Cuz like clearly
to build out where I like manufacturing
facilities. Like at some point you had
to go from I'm just responding to oh,
I'm going to think this through a little
bit. Like here's how we're going to
deploy capital.
Like what size were you when this
started to get a bit more disciplined?
I'm looking for a better word here. I
just I don't know what it is, but
>> don't throw out disciplined in terms of
me. That
one doesn't work.
>> Uh
but like
>> [laughter]
>> thoughtful, maybe?
Um I don't know.
Uh I would say
I learned a lot of this in the last 6
months. I learned a lot more the 6
months before that, the 6 months before
that. It's not like magically in 2018
that it all came together. Like I'm
better this year than I was last year. I
remember being on stage at Commerce
Roundtable speaking and Nick Shackelford
was there and he seriously asked a
question like, "What if I don't feel
like I'm ready to do the jump I need to
do?"
And I said, "None of us are ready. None
of us have ever done this thing before.
Like the thing that Operators podcast
does better than anything is you guys
talk at a high level
from experience of actually doing things
to a lot of these companies that are 1
million and 2 and 4 and 5. And they're
looking for something that you guys say
that's going to help them in their
day-to-day life.
And I really think the number one thing
that I've told people that's helped is
you've never done it before until you do
it.
So, when did I learn it? I sure as hell
didn't know it at the beginning.
I didn't know it the second year. I
didn't know it the third. Each year I've
gotten a little bit better and now
looking back, I feel like I've got it
more in hand,
but I'm just entering the new room where
things are bigger and people are talking
billions instead of hundreds of millions
just like I was entering rooms where
people talking millions rather than
50,000. You get better as you go along.
The money side came because you had to
learn because
it's your squeeze down. You're squeezed
in June when you have no sales. You're
squeezed when your revenue is picking it
up. You're squeezed when taxes come.
Like you're squeezed all the time, so
you just get better at forecasting that
out. Everyone thinks I look ahead 5 10
years. I don't. I look ahead 1 year.
That's it. I figure if I do that 1 year,
the rest of it going to come together.
That's been a common pattern I've
in in founders I talk to at scale is
they actually don't look that far out.
No. Right? It's like typically 6 months
back, 6 months forward and they're just
rolling all the time. Like the forecasts
are rolling.
There's none of these like, you know,
3-year business plans, none of that.
It is straight up like here is the
furthest I can see in my business and
even then, there's a lot of assumptions.
You do those forward-looking statements
like a lot. So, some of the worst hires,
I shouldn't say worst hires. They're
they're good people, but the the worst
culture fits at Ridge were traditional
finance people who wanted to do a 3-year
finance. Like like like a 3-year
projection, right? Being like, "Hey,
like here and like they're trying to
build our projections based on like
website visits and stuff." And it's just
not how we operate. I'm going to do
whatever is best in the moment right now
to make the most amount of money and it
is just a series of hop scotches to try
to figure out what the the best idea is.
It is not like this like forward path
like this is exactly what we're going to
do because you just you can't predict
the future in this business. Who would
have saw tariffs coming? Who would have
saw Silicon Valley Bank blowing up? You
know what I mean? Like who would have
saw this stuff happening? Yeah,
day-to-day there's just so many changes
in this business. Like Sean, the the
last the over the last 10 days
were
for a bunch of reasons we're producing
uh one of our lenders asked for like an
updated 3-year forecast. So, we're
getting on a call with them and I'm with
some of my investors
and I get asked this question. Every
time I get asked this question, it's
like here's the 3-year budget. They're
like, "Well, what's your confidence
level on that?" I'm like,
"Zero, bro."
Like Like if I could see 36 months in
the future,
I wouldn't be talking to you right now.
Totally.
What what I say on that, Matt, is my
confidence level that we're going to hit
that goal is there, but all of these
bull numbers in the middle are just made
up, right? Like they just I'm flying to
LA today and I'm talking to an equity
potential equity partner that I've been
working with for 4 years, okay?
And I flew to LA on December 12th
and it's fun cuz it's going to be 3
months. And we gave them all of our
numbers and our projections for next
year and now they have all these people
in the rooms hitting keys and working
with our financial people to make sure
our finances are right.
They'd missed the 3 months of me saying
I saw where we were on December 12th. I
didn't like it enough, so I'm making
major changes that those numbers on that
screen are not going to show what I've
done in 3 months. It's major stuff. It
is major major, but they don't see the
day-to-day and the week. They just say
we start here and to get here, the
computer goes here, divide those months
by 36 and here's you got. It's such bull
It is the broken way that finance people
and linear minds look at things. Drives
me crazy. I I understand why though,
guys. Like I I really do understand why
because
a a lot of consumer, there's a lot of
history in consumer and most of that
history has been in traditional B2B
wholesale retail agreements. So, like it
actually was
easier to like know what Target's going
to buy from you over the next 12 months
or 18 months because Target tells you
like this is how much we're going to buy
over the next 18 months. So, like
there's a lot of muscle
in the analyst side or like the banking
side around what they think a consumer
business should be able to tell you.
They don't they're just not up to date
with like, "Listen, man, we've we've
been algorithmic for a while.
Right? I get hasn't like the news hasn't
made it to you yet,
but like there's this e-commerce thing
and things fluctuate a lot in this
e-commerce thing and like Zuckerberg
can't really tell me
what my return is going to look like in
in 3 months, you know? There's no
guarantees.
So, I I think Curtis part of the problem
is like you're dealing with a bunch of
people with
like to Sean's point on like these hires
are tricky.
Even if you don't hire them, you're
going to deal with people like this.
They have a lot of muscle built up over
a long time that is just not the right
muscle.
Every SaaS company says they are
AI-powered, but very few can explain
what it actually does for the revenue of
my brand. This is why Postscript's
approach stood out to us. They don't
just build AI for demos or buzzwords,
they built it to drive real incremental
revenue. Postscript's AI called Shopper,
it shows up inside of SMS at moments
with real buyer intent when shoppers are
likely asking questions, hesitating,
maybe even about to drop off. Shopper
can answer product questions instantly,
answer questions about fit,
availability, recommendations, order
issues, the kinds of stuff that people
usually bounce for. This means more
conversions, higher AOV, less lost
demand, so you are driving more revenue
and doing it more efficiently. Check out
Shopper from Postscript. We use it at
Pillow, which is why I am telling you to
check it out.
Yeah, the the flexibility
in e-commerce is that
like you have to be flexible enough that
if you see something, you can exploit
it, right? You know, our biggest product
line this year, it'll do $40 million. It
didn't exist 12 months ago. So, it's
like you know, we we've added a new
product line to our business. It is It
is our our third or fourth biggest
product line. Didn't exist 12 months
ago. And so, if I had a 36-year your
Sorry, 36-month chart, it wouldn't be on
there cuz it didn't exist, right? You
know, we have to find these pockets of
of either demand or low like, you know,
low-cost attention or whatever so you
actually exploit them and grow. Um I
want to talk about though the squeeze.
Curtis, you you brought this up a couple
times. I think the reason why being an
e-commerce person is the one of the
worst things to be and why it's such a
hard job is like you're getting squeezed
by everybody all the time, right? Uh and
maybe maybe just unpack your experience
with that. Like, you know, when you're
actually trying to fund this growth, you
are you are looking for dollars that
don't exist and looking for margin that
doesn't exist. So, what are some unique
places you found that while you're
getting squeezed?
Well, you're getting squeezed and
everyone around you see that you're
growing. So, they all think that well, a
real business would have all of this
money and you've got to be making all of
this money. You're worth a lot of money.
So, you get employees coming in who are
saying, "Wow, nice building, right?
That's really nice." They don't know
that I actually knocked down the wall
and built it and paint the whole damn
thing myself on the weekends. And
they're like, "Well, I need to make more
money because this is awesome." And I'm
like, "Yeah, we don't do that around
here."
You know, we They're like, "Well,
there's another job that pays more,
but I don't like them. You pay less and
I like you. So, I want to work with you
cuz I like you and I want you to pay
what they pay." And I'm like, "That's
the choices we make in the world, dude.
You trust me enough that this is going
to grow and you jump on this team and
you you
grit it out or you go where someone's
going to give you the short-term money."
So, the first thing is your employees.
You got to tell them from the word go,
"Hey, you're Go make more someplace else
and it will be the dumbest decision
you've ever made." I say that in
interviews with people. Like, they'll be
talking and I'll be listening. Yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. And then I'll
say, "Hey, if I offered this job at
20,000 less, your smartest thing is to
take this job because in 1 year you're
going to be a different person cuz we're
going to stretch and grow and you're
going to get skills and you're going to
be awesome. So, part of that money comes
from you can't have a labor force that
is overpaid, that has high expectations
of getting fat at the end unreasonable
amounts of money that you may not have.
That's number one. Then is the supply
chain. What I did differently and and
Matt, I really loved what you said there
is, "Hey, Target, they got this stuff
figured out 12 years ahead of time."
That's because they're ordering
materials that are going to factories
that are being men that are on sho- on
boats that are taking 2 months to come
across, that are going and they're
seasonal. So, they've already chosen 12
months ahead of time.
We had a new ad hit on TikTok
and we moved it over to Meta and it just
skyrocketed everything. So, a bag that
was going to sell 110,000 bags is now
projected at 300,000 bags this year.
An additional 190,000
bags on a line that makes a thousand a
week, you got to make changes, right? If
I was dealing in China, I'm screwed. We
ran down that day, changed it up and had
within 5 days those things kicking out
in in a truck on the way to Dallas. So,
part of Shawn, your answer to your
question is when Cash is doing it is
like, "How can I turn my product into
cash faster and more efficient? I can't
spend money on product that's not going
to sell."
I just can't spend it on there. You
can't I can't be as far ahead on that. I
have to make the exact right products at
the right time. That was one of it.
Um
I use credit cards.
I used American Express. I
You know, that's it. Like, you just you
make it work. You We don't have the
money. What I used to say to everybody
is if you want to make more money, if we
want to get here, then we need to do
this. And what's one of the biggest
changes in my company? We were an Etsy
company.
We were paying everybody like $12 an
hour, I think, uh to make our little
journals in Portland. There was only a
few employees. And my
a young lady I was working with said,
"We need to get everyone up to $15 an
hour."
And I said, "Look at the money. We only
bring this in. We can't like there's no
money to pay them $15 an hour." This was
years and years ago.
She said, "How do we pay them?" I said,
"If you could sell from this many totes
to this many,
we can give the cash flow that we can
then give them the raise."
When they had that motivation, the way
to make them, to make them cheaper, to
make the right bags, to do the
photography, to get it online on Etsy,
to start receiving the cash, within 7
days we tripled the amount of totes we
did and we gave everybody a raise.
So, what we did is we tied performance
and money to the success of the company.
You get more when we do better.
By being transparent about the money.
I don't know if that answered your
question because I don't know Hey, I'm
going to be honest with you. I I don't
know how I did it. I really don't. Like,
at times I look back and I'm like, we
should have been knocked out of business
a bunch of times.
No, dude, I I'm right there with you.
You know, on the people point before we
leave the people point, um
you know, Ridge spends 8% of revenue on
all people. So, that is bonuses, uh
401Ks, taxes, insurance, salaries,
whatever. 8% of revenue. It includes all
of our executives. We have a very large
executive suite. Includes our in-house
lawyer, whatever else. I'm just curious
where you guys track towards that 8%,
you know. We're exactly 8%. Oh, cool.
So, so Curtis, you're you're right there
with us, brother. Well, well, I our
projections are 7 to 9, but we're
currently at 8. And with the retail
growth, we with the income growth, we'll
be we should stay right around 8. I was
talking to Maverick. He's like, "Wow,
that seems pretty low. Like, everyone's
more than that." And I'm like, "Well,
that's our advantage, dude.
Our advantage is to not hire those
people and could build out. You don't
Just cuz your income doesn't go up
doesn't mean you build your company to
fulfill that. You don't start spending
money cuz that's what other companies
do. I like the 8%. It feels really,
really good. To me, I'm going to I'm
going to be an [__] here. It feels
high.
I wish we could have right now we're in
the world where can you get one person
to do three people's jobs? It's like
when we started the company and there's
only five of us and everybody had to do
three or four jobs. I want to return to
that world. I want to return to say,
"Hey, you know more about this. You
should be overseeing this because these
two work together and if we had you just
doing that, I could get rid of a salary.
You could make more. The company would
be more successful." It's just me. I'm
just I guess I'm kind of thrifty.
Our target Our target this year is 8.
Like, we're Some of that's going to come
from
right-sizing. Some of it's going to come
from growth.
Uh productivity. Like, there's a bunch
of stuff, but
8 is what we want to get to. I think
right now it's Curtis, when you say 8,
are you including your factory workers?
Do they all go into cost?
>> is all cost of goods. Okay.
Uh
>> All of the folks in Mexico are cost of
goods. Yeah. Uh but the cost of goods by
making here is much less than if we buy
from somebody else. Like, if I could buy
the product
>> that part. It's more just how you
account for like people costs, right?
>> all of our executives in Mexico are on
that 8%. Okay. So, it's like non
non-production labor. So, basically like
full-time full-time equivalent sort of
workers that are not making the goods.
>> design here. Design is part of that 8%.
We have photography here. It's part of
that 8%. We But the actual workers who
are actually physically making the bag
are part of part of a cost of goods.
Yeah, and warehouse staff should be the
same thing, right? Like, you know, if
you have a 3PL
>> of logistics. Um you know, on the 8%.
So, Curtis, I'm with you that it also
feels high. I think the future is 5% and
for a very long time it was 10 10% was
like the gold standard. I think 8 is the
new 10 and I think 5 is going to be the
new 8. So, I think I I'm right there
with you, brother. I think It's not
being thrifty. It's It's just with AI
agents, it's where the future is going.
Yeah. Those are hard decisions.
>> math on my side cuz I got to back out
the factory that I'm trying to do it,
but
8 I think is the right number. I That
like we just talked about this yesterday
here. So. Yeah, and I And Ridge, we're
not going to cut head count. What we're
going to do is grow.
It's like if you can keep head count the
same and your business doubles, that 8
becomes 4, right? And I think keeping
your business
with no additional hires is hard, but
it's going to be very few additional
hires, right? I think these businesses
are just going to get way, way, way more
efficient. Um
Okay, so you're using credit card
points. You're you're You're convincing
people to work for you for less because
you are more likable, throwback to our
previous episode. Um But yeah, dude,
that squeeze, it's so hard being an
e-commerce merchant because like, you
have to get the supplies, you have to
get the raw goods, you have to transform
them, you have to pay for ads, and then
you have to get the inventory in
people's hands, and then you get your
money from Shopify, but then you got to
buy more inventory to do it again. And
as your business scales up, it's really
hard to do that. If you ever take a flat
year, you'll make a ton of money. You'll
have a bunch of cash flow. I've no idea
what
what what to do with it.
Um
So, Curtis, let's go back to that 2021
meeting.
Wells Fargo totally screws you. You end
up You're like, "I'm going to figure
this out," right? Um Since that point,
your business has quadrupled, right? Or
tripled. Your business is way bigger
than the 2021 point.
>> way bigger uh and we're way more
profitable. Like, that's just the game.
I I used to
I think as an entrepreneur, I was more
of a salesman. So, I always thought I
could sell my way out of any problem or
just market my way out of any problems.
Like, "Oh, we need to pay for that? I
will make more money and we will pay for
that." And then you look back at the end
of the year and you're like, "Where's
the money at?" Right?
And I realized it's kind of like you see
these lines behind me. If if you're
watching this on YouTube, you get to see
that there's a a stitching factory
behind me. If you're just listening to
it, you don't get to see that. And what
we found out is if you just start a line
every week and they say make as many as
you can, they'll make a certain amount
and they'll say that's the most we could
make. So, we put up computer screens
interlocked on every single line, so it
has a big screen, like a big screen TV
in colors, and each hour it changes
colors to see where they are on pace.
Are they in white? Are they in green
ahead or in the
are they in red? And what we found out
by marking that down,
efficiency went up 28% without saying or
doing anything, just keeping track hour
to hour of where your money is going or
in their case what they're actually
making, made them all more efficient.
They were dropping
efficiency where they didn't know it.
Same thing in money.
It's the once I finally said, "Whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa. That's really start.
Let's break the year down. Here's what
it is. Logistics, you only have that.
Cost of goods, not good enough. We
cannot be at that. We need to be 2%
lower." No, no, no, no, no. We need you
to be there. You cannot get our merch
cannot be above this. Once we did that,
gave them goals that they could use
every week, every month,
all of the sudden cash just starts
spitting out the other end.
And if I had not done that, we would
have worked just as hard, thought we
were doing the same things, and the cash
wouldn't have been there at the end.
Yeah. No, well, dude, it's it's an
amazing story, and I'm so glad uh you
were able to bootstrap your way through
all of that, and now you have this big
profitable asset you own at the end.
What's up, operators? Welcome to the
Richpanel ad read. Richpanel has been a
sponsor for over 12 months. I've been a
paying customer for over 12 months, and
guess what? I just renewed the pay again
for another year. We have cut our SaaS
bill in half, and automation dropped our
cost per ticket by 70%. Our CSAT has
also improved from 88%, which is still
really good, to 96% best in class, all
powered by Richpanel. I told them last
year, "Hey, you guys need to do the same
thing with returns." And now Richpanel
has a returns portal. It's built to cut
down your tickets and convert more
refunds into exchanges. They do the
heavy lifting, data import,
self-service, retention flows, team
training, all of it, and they'll be live
in 2 weeks. If you want to save 30%
guaranteed on help desk and now returns,
book a demo.
All right, yeah, Matt, I just want you
to explain venture capital to us, right?
So, me and Curtis bootstrapped. And so,
the question is
Matt,
you funded growth a different way. How
did you end up funding growth for for
your brands, and why did you choose
venture capital?
Okay, so we we bootstrapped till about
10 million in revenue. Bootstrap being
like
I put up the first capital, like most of
the first working capital.
I had another company
that like Pela basically grew up inside
that business. So, like we we took
office space.
We used an actual office as a warehouse.
That was also interesting, so it wasn't
a garage, Curtis, but like I was on the
sixth floor
of a brick and beam building in a
110-year-old
like brick and beam building in Toronto,
and they used to have to come up the
damn elevator, which is 100 [snorts]
years old, to get the packages every day
to go out to customers. So, we would
pick package beside the desks of all the
software developers that worked for me
in my first company.
So, we we funded the first bit of Pela's
journey
off of my own personal balance sheet.
Um so, I guess in that sense it's like
also a little unfair cuz I wasn't really
starting from like zero. I put I think a
quarter million bucks in or 400 grand in
like pretty easily at the beginning.
Um
like spread out. I didn't just like
write the check. It's like I could just
afford the I could cash flow it. So,
that was the first 10 million bucks. We
brought on venture
I would say in hindsight I shouldn't
have done it. We should have just
figured out how to bootstrap the way
that Curtis did it because for Pela,
the only reason we needed outside
capital was when we decided to start
building our own factory. Then it was
like, "Oh, this is expensive." Like
buying injection molding machines and
printers and
building out a facility, like all that
just is takes cash. So, we raised a bit
of money for Pela.
Uh and then along came the idea for
Lomi.
Lomi, we're like, "Oh, we're going to
need money." Like hardware, firmware,
software, like this is a
nightmare product to develop. Uh that's
when we raised real venture capital.
So, that's like the the sequence of
things. I am not a fan of venture in
consumer. I think these are just
incredibly hard companies to underwrite,
too.
Um
the outcomes just aren't as big.
Like they're just
compared to like what tech used to be.
Although, I don't know, maybe SaaS
multiples coming down is going to make
consumer look really good for venture.
Um
So, Sean, I think
you know, my view was like
uh high CapEx gave us a reason
to raise outside capital.
Like I could justify it that way. Like,
"Oh, I'm going to spend like tens of
millions of dollars on CapEx and R&D and
building facilities and all that crap."
That's why we did it. In hindsight, I
would raise a lot less money if at all
for Pela.
How do you how do you fund growth right
now? Is it a cash flowing machine?
You're profitable?
>> yeah, now we're uh Pela produces cash.
Um
it's like good free cash flow. Like
that's a good business.
Right? Uh
and for the reasons that Curtis is
highlighting, like when we get a winning
product, it's very easy for us to scale
up cuz we own the production.
Um so, my
working capital needs in Pela are
extremely low. Like I am probably as
close to negative working capital as you
can get in consumer.
Without like
negotiating 180 payment like day payment
terms with a factory. Like or with
another supplier. So, like we largely
sell
and then make and ship is sort of the
sequence of events for our
direct-to-consumer business.
Um
Yeah, I want to I want to go back to the
equation that makes cash flowing a
business very difficult and assume
zero-day terms on everything, right? So,
like you pay a supplier and then they
give you inventory. Well, that inventory
has to trans like even if you're not
doing what Curtis is doing and building
it yourself, if you're just buying from
China, putting it on a boat, you're
waiting 30 to 60 days, and then you're
selling it. Let's say let's say you sell
all the stuff immediately, right? Um
you know,
the then you have to take that money and
then go back to the supplier and buy
more things. And like that handover,
that that cash conversion cycle is what
ends up killing you, right? Um and it's
why you need some sort of unfair
advantage. Like where are you putting
leverage in the system? You either can
have a bunch of money, right? Which is
what Matt cash Matt took his own
personal money and put into his
business, and that's how he got it off
the ground. Or you can use debt or
investors or whatever, somebody
injecting money into the system, right?
To add liquidity. Or you can go to your
supplier and you can make them give you
it before you can start selling it. But
something has to change or break in that
system cuz when you're talking about
paying people yet, we're not talking
about paying taxes yet. Like the reality
is
you
the equation doesn't work unless there's
some sort of slack or leverage in the
system, and you have to get that from
somewhere. Either you bring the money,
somebody brings the money, or you change
the payment terms. That that that's what
what made Lomi so difficult as a
business was that uh because it was a
new thing that no factory had ever made
before,
we effectively prepaid for all of our
inventory for the first
year and a half or 2 years.
And like at $240
a machine
in like per
to buy in cost,
at really fast scale,
uh
yeah, we needed outside capital. I'm
like, "I can't write a $12 million
check."
Like, sorry. Um
So, I think
I I don't know how useful that is for
people listening because like most
product in most consumer companies are
are going to come out of factories that
know how to make the thing.
Like they make lots of that thing.
So, you should be able to get far better
terms than like prepaying for inventory.
Although, when you're a new business, I
don't know, maybe that's like actually
just part of it, too. It's like there's
no relationship there, so like show up
with cash, right? Um
Yeah, also, if you're new, the best
factories don't want to work with you,
and they don't want to give you terms.
So, you're you're going to be stuck
working with a bad factory. Uh and if
they're giving you terms, then things
are really bad. They have no other
clients. So,
Yeah, that factory that I I think like
for most brands,
what Curtis hit on around like
partnership with your supplier,
the the I would start investing in that
relationship really early. Like make
yourself a good partner,
um and then it'll build, right? Like
you'll get better terms. Uh sometimes
you're going to have to help them out,
too. Like we've definitely had
situations
where we would working with our
factories cuz we still have some
factories that supply us some products,
right?
Where I've done what Curtis is talking
about. I've we've sat down with them and
just said,
"Okay, like what do you need from us to
extend us better payment terms?" And
we've had times where it's like, "Look,
if you can give us some amount of cash
now, that'll show our bank
that we're a better borrower in China,
right? And then we'll be able to extend
you better terms because we'll get
better terms from the bank. So, we'll
extend them the cash upfront. Say like,
"Here's $100,000." They'll go get better
terms and then immediately cycle that
back to us. That only comes from having
a good working relationship with the
supplier. So, like I think Sean, most
brands that are going to listen to this,
your best source of funding is going to
be like working capital leverage is
probably going to be your supply chain.
Like it's most likely. And that's And
like, you know,
is that's how we were able to do it,
right? We've never taken any
investment. We barely have a line of
credit. All of our leverage came from
suppliers. So, from $2 million a year to
$200 million a year, it's it's all come
from suppliers.
Um look, we talked about
payroll as a percentage of revenue. I
think the next thing we should talk
about is gross margin because this whole
thing doesn't work unless you have good
gross margin. And I'm going to explain
my definition of gross margin. I'll give
you guys Ridge's gross margin numbers
and then you guys can chime in with with
what you think the minimum requirement
is. So, you know, if you have an MSRP of
$100, okay?
And it costs you $10 to make,
that is a product margin of 90%. But you
have to you have to factor in what
you're actually selling it for. So, your
MSRP is different than your sales price.
If you have discounts or whatever,
right? And then also, it doesn't count
for gross margin unless you're getting
it to the customer's door, right? Like
if that includes wholesale fees, if that
includes payment processing fees, if it
includes shipment to the customer's
door,
it doesn't matter if you don't have to
cost you 10 bucks to make, it's what
when is the customer fulfilled with that
order and then when does the money
clear? So, that's the actual gross
margin number people should be talking
about.
Public companies do this a bunch of
different ways. Hermes puts the cost of
their machines and their buildings
inside of that gross margin because they
make all their own stuff. They're like,
"If I don't buy this machine, if I don't
buy this building, I can't make the
thing, so it's part of my cost of goods,
right?"
>> They don't capitalize that?
No, I mean I I Look, I haven't looked at
their their earnings in a long time, but
uh you know, French company or French
company stuff, I don't really know how
they're how they're doing it, but
>> I I suspect I suspect that what the way
that we work, Sean, like so yes, gross
margin
is like the total cost to make and
deliver the thing to the customer. Like
make, sell, and deliver the thing to the
customer,
not including marketing costs. That's
not inside of your gross margin, right?
Uh that's like we're then going to move
over to contribution.
But I would suspect that Curtis and I
financially probably do very similar
things. Like we take all the labor costs
and overhead associated with the factory
and then that basically get That's your
COGS number for us.
So, like we don't buy a product from a
factory. It's like all that stuff, if I
made 100,000 cases this month, it just
gets divided amongst 100,000 cases. In
Curtis' math, I do it a little bit
opposite.
Uh I say, "What's our cost of goods?"
And we're getting that down every year.
So, from some bags that are at 28, 29%
to small leather goods that are less, we
want to up that. We want to be at 25.2%
of cost of goods throughout the year for
a couple hundred million in sales,
right? So, 25. And we say all money that
comes down here to Mexico to make this
product or goes international has a
strict budget to be at that 20.5. That's
how much money they have. They have to
make all the product we need, okay?
Logistics, we had a couple bad years in
logistics
uh because we're expanding retail and we
have to send things that are more
expensive, we've added that in and that
can be a pain in the ass, but the
marketing is different there.
But we were about 16%
because we sell big packages for low low
margins. Uh
we have moved over to a company called
Flexport.
Um I met the CEO, great guy. We really
got along, had some really good things
and uh they said, "Hey, we'll pay you $2
million."
And they ran our numbers and they said,
"We'll save you $6 million next year
guaranteed on your shipping." $2 million
plus $6 million.
So, we're like, "Okay, sounds good.
We'll we'll take that money." So, we'll
be about 12.5 all in with logistics this
next year.
So, with the product plus that, uh we're
going to be under 33% with the making
the product, getting it to uh Dallas,
uh shipping it to the consumer, all in
product, everything about 33%.
Yeah, which is fantastic. I think I
Those are public company numbers, you
know, I think Yeti's at 54% all in,
right? So, you're you're you're mugging
them, Curtis. Um Ridge Ridge's uh
a lighter weight good and typically
probably sits at a higher margin good
than you. So, we're at like 75 to 80 all
in. That includes logistics, shipping to
to people's doors. And
if these numbers we're saying scare you,
this is probably
what you need to be at, somewhere
between Curtis and me to actually be
able to cash flow your business.
It or else you're just going to be
setting money on fire and not be able to
grow. You you really need margins like
this, 66%
all in including COGS, including
fulfillment, including everything. Like
payment processing, put it all in there,
right? Like this number should scare
you, but that's what you need to be at.
Matt, do you agree or disagree? I
completely agree. I think we're talking
about
durables
right now, like consumer durables.
Uh or I guess I don't know Curtis if you
call yourself a durable, but like
non-consumable, right? So, it's not
food, it's not beverage, it's not
supplement, like it's none of that
stuff. Um
I think that is
I mean I can
we are very close to you, Sean.
Longtime sponsor Northbeam is launching
incrementality later this quarter. This
means that you can now have the trifecta
of marketing measurement all in one
platform. That is multi-touch
attribution, media mix modeling, and
incrementality holdouts all inside of
Northbeam. You can automate that lift
testing end-to-end, unify results with
your MTA and your MMM. This is a lot of
letters, but if you know, you know, and
you can start to cut what doesn't work
and you can scale what works. You can do
this all with confidence. This is why
this is such an incredible add to
Northbeam. Northbeam's incrementality
measures what results marketing is
actually generating, not just what
they're claiming credit for. As a CEO,
that's like music to my ears. Sign up
now and you can lock in 50% off
unlimited tests for the year.
Yeah. And I'm You make the distinction
around consumables because
yes,
the reason why these numbers have to be
like this is because we're all paying a
meta tax of 25 to 50% of our revenue,
right? And the idea with consumables is
you're going to pay a meta tax of 100%
of your revenue, but then
you you're going to stop acquiring new
customers at some point and just rake in
the cash from these from these beautiful
cohorts. TBD if that happens to you, you
know what I mean? That is That is the
36-month game plan that we're talking
about earlier. It's like you really have
to be believing in the future to to pull
that off. You have to have those cohort
values. But anyway, the the reason I
bring this up is This is a This is about
funding growth, this whole episode. You
can't fund growth if you have broken
unit economics, right? So,
you like the reason why Curtis talked
about 8% of revenue going to people and
that number going down over time, that
is the reality. You're probably
listening to this, and you probably have
15% or a 12% or 8%. Like there's a
reason why I was broke until Ridge did
$100 million a year, right? Curtis, I
assume you were broke until you guys
were doing $100 million a year, too,
right?
Absolutely broke.
Yeah, like it's because it's very hard
to extract capital out of this machine,
especially if you're growing, right?
Now, if you want to take a down year or
a flat year, you should be rich as hell.
And And the reason for that is because
the there'll be a pile-up of capital in
the system, right? Right now, the the
system's incredibly lean because all the
capital goes to buy new inventory to
keep to keep the whole machine growing.
And if you ever want to just not grow
for a year, you'll find yourself being
incredibly rich. Like uh at Ridge, we
call it the waterfall theory. And And
it's because we're always chasing that
waterfall. It's like, "Dude, at some
point there's going to be a bunch of
money we're totally going to get." It
hasn't happened yet, but you know, we're
we're counting on it. Um
And then Matt, because you're a venture
capital funded, how
when do you when do you get money? Do
you just never?
Uh well, it's a
This is why I don't think you should
that the pref stack becomes your
your problem when you're venture funded,
right? So, depending on how much money
you bring in,
your preferred shareholders on a on an
exit, they get more. Well, sorry, they
get their money back first. They don't
necessarily get more. There's a lot of
other terms that go in there. So, in my
case, Sean, I think I said it is like
the first three episodes we ever
recorded. Like when we built this
company and we decided to take venture,
the minute you do that, you're basically
committing to a hero or a zero.
And that's like that is the world you
live in.
We're trying to
move the company more to a private
equity. Like we want to just be
consistently profitable and generate
cash and then that's how we provide
returns to our shareholders. That's a
That's a whole other set of battles,
guys. Like trying to get
investors to like change the way that
they've underwritten your company after
they've underwritten your company is a
diff like we don't need to talk about
that today, but that is like really hard
to do. Um
No, Sean, I mean
the reason I'm doing this like for every
I'm already rich. Like I've already sold
a company. Like I wouldn't go and raise
venture capital and try to like do
something really hard where you get paid
nothing
if I didn't already have all the money.
Like
let's just be really honest that there's
a giant safety net.
Uh
I just I think it's insane
of a path. Like don't do it.
It's
the best advice I can give you. Like
unless you're already you have rich.
Yeah, if you want to change the world
venture capital is a great way to do it,
but if you want to sell phone cases or
bags or wallets, I think I think it's
one of the worst ways to go. Yeah, 100%.
5 minutes left. What what do we want to
talk about? Curtis, what did we miss
that you think is incredibly important
for the audience to know?
You didn't miss anything. I I want to I
came on about episode 81 or two. Uh so
about halfway through this so far the
journey so far.
And Matt said something important about
manufacturers. Like, "Hey everybody,
don't just think that starting the
manufacturing is the way to go. It's
hard as
He said earlier, "Hey, when you get a
product that really takes off, your your
manufacturing it's easy." No, everybody
none of that easy. Like it's Like
nothing that I do is easy. I do it
because it works better as a long-term
thing and it works out, but none of this
is easy. Uh you get better at it so it
looks easier to other people. And then
you forget how hard it was so you
pretend like, "Oh, it was pretty easy. I
started doing art festivals and I built
a company worth blank amount of money,
right?" No, no, no, no. This is all
hard.
So that's number one. Number two, Sean,
you were saying so well
that hey, where are your where are your
margins at? I am approached by people as
I'm sure both of you are because the
Operators podcast has become so well
known for D2C. Uh everybody knows it.
About people who are at 1 million and 2
million and they're not making money and
they come they say, "Let me tell you my
model.
Uh I'm buying t-shirts for 40 and I'm
selling them for 80."
And you're like, "Yeah, uh don't do it."
"Well, that's the only way I can The
quality's really good and people will
buy it at that." And you know, I I
haven't done my shipping and my returns
or anything else in there. And the
model's just broke from the start,
right? You've got us get a model that
actually works if you want to scale that
thing. You can't overpay for your
product. Have no advantage just to sell
it low so you have revenue coming in. I
have met with companies. I was meeting
with Mariana and I met and I'm going to
do make say this really quick.
I met with this guy who's doing about 45
million a year. And we just stopped in
cuz I like their company and met with
them. And after about an hour I said,
"Hey, can everybody leave the room? I
just want to talk to this guy." I'm
like, "Dude, what's wrong?"
And he's like, "Oh, nothing.
Everything's great." I'm like,
"Something's wrong." He's like, "Dude,
I'm broke. I've got kids. I don't I'm
not making any money. And all my friends
are telling me I'm killing it, right?
Everyone's saying congratulations. You
started an apartment. Now you're doing
45 million You're in Dick's Sporting
Goods. Like you must be killing it."
He's like, "I'm worried."
And I'm like, "Yeah, figure out your
models. You know, you're not making
money here and here. Like don't listen
to the the roar of the applause cuz you
tell people things are good and they
tell you you're awesome and you use that
to justify not getting better. Find
better margins. Change your company. Get
a model that works. Figure out how to be
profitable, how to scale, and how to
make money. And make the hard damn
decisions."
I think Sean, the actual thing on what
Curtis is saying
part of the equation is
uh you might just be trying to grow too
damn fast.
Like if you look at your your operating
margin, so like there's gross margin,
there's contribution margin, and there's
like how much can I actually generate?
Just do the math on how much growth can
you actually afford. You don't need to
triple.
Like you just don't. You know, like what
growth can you afford? Maybe that's the
right answer.
Like Like do you Do you have to stress
the system to the point where it almost
breaks every month?
Like I thought you were I mean like the
whole point of being a founder
and and bootstrapped is like you can
choose.
So like if you're choosing to break your
business by growing that fast, maybe the
answer is to choose to grow a little
slower and compound over longer period
of time. I don't know. Maybe I'm just an
idiot. That seems like a option.
No, Matt and Curtis, you guys are both
right. And I just want to say, you know,
we're not in the trophy business. Like
e-commerce is not the trophy business.
And And what I mean by that is you don't
get a trophy for
telling people how great things are. You
don't get a trophy for growing fast. The
only trophy is Do you Do you make any
money? You know what I mean? It's like
there's like you you don't get a trophy
be like, "Yeah, dude, you built a big
great business and you you you took no
money for yourself and whatever." It's
just like we're not that business, bro.
Like you have to be able to take money
out of this thing. And And growing
slower or being ruthless about OPEX,
being ruthless about margins, like that
That is the only way you survive to play
another day. So we're you know
uh for all for all of our Gen Z
audience, it's like this is a Battle
Royale. You have to be last to survive,
okay? It's not a high score game if that
makes any sense. You can win by just
staying in the bushes doing nothing and
waiting for everybody to kill each other
and being the last guy out there. That's
how you can win. You you can't win a
game you're not in.
And I think the goal number one, stay in
the game as long as you possibly can,
ideally forever, and take a much longer
view
on a physical goods business.
Uh get the
off of X and or whatever the hell we're
calling it these days and listening to
like, "I went from zero to 300 million
in in I mean, we're guilty for this cuz
we have these people on our podcast.
Just get off of X.
Consumer goods
is a very difficult bucket of companies
to build. They take longer than you
think they do. Like if you're young and
you're getting started,
be prepared for a 10-year journey. Like
go into it with that mentality and just
go slower. That is like the best advice
I could give somebody. The greatest
quote about time is a Bill Gates quote
and I love this one. He says we
overestimate what we can do in a year,
we underestimate what we can do in 10.
Because no D2C person is figuring out
10. You ask us for a three-year model
and we're like, "Kiss my ass. I'm
thinking So
I'm thinking seasons. Don't talk to me
about 10." But 10's real.
10 comes along. After after 8 and 9
comes 10. Yeah, man, I've been doing
this for 22 years. Like it just
takes time.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, this is my 10-year anniversary at
Ridge this year. So
That's awesome. That's how long it
takes, guys. All right, that's been
another amazing episode of the Operators
podcast. Curtis, I hear you're going to
be on way more of these episodes in the
future. You're the new Jason. So we love
having you here, Curtis. Thank you for
being here. Matt, you're a great guy.
I'll talk to you guys later. Goodbye.
>> [music]